Denis Nagornyi

SENIOR PYTHON ENGINEER | PYTHON/DJANGO DEVELOPER | TBILISI, GEORGIA (GMT+4)



8+ YEARS OF EXPERTISE

+995 511 228 446 Linkedin denis.nagornyi0@gmail.com

Profile

Senior Python Engineer with 8+ years of experience in building scalable web applications and custom solutions for startups and enterprises. Strong in algorithms, problem-solving, and domain-driven design.

Known for delivering solutions that address 80% of business needs with 20% of the effort. Equally effective as a team player or a "one-person orchestra," handling everything from requirements to DevOps.

Skills

Backend: Python, Django, Flask, Tornado, Fastapi, AsynclO, Pydantic, PostgresSQL, MongoDB, Redis,

Memcached, Golang

Env: Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Lambda, GCP, Scaleway, Cognito, oVirt, Opennebula, Git, Linux, Terraform

Experience

SENIOR PYTHON DEVELOPER AT EMERGING TRAVEL GROUP. NOVEMBER 2023 - NOW;

Developed a property management system tailored for short-term rental hosts.

- Designed and implemented a custom matching algorithm, tripling the number of listed properties (+50,000 apartments) on the platform, driving significant revenue growth.
- Enabled the onboarding of 20,000 additional properties in key high-demand regions through a streamlined, data-driven approach, with potential for even greater results upon full-scale ETL implementation.
- Simplified and accelerated property activation by addressing key host pain points, significantly increasing platform availability and competitiveness in critical markets.

This solution not only enhanced supply acquisition but also positioned the company ahead of competitors with minimal investment of time and resources.

SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER I AT SUPER DISPATCH INC., KANSAS (REMOTE) FEBRUARY 2022 – NOVEMBER 2023; 1 YR 10 MOS

Development and support of web app backend, mobile application and public APIs

- Optimized Elasticsearch documents to set up a responsive search with a P99 latency of 3 seconds.
- Improved system availability to 99.87% and reduced bug resolution time from 2 weeks to just a few hours by implementing Datadog monitoring.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER AT TETRIKA SCHOOL, MOSCOW. JANUARY 2021 – FEBRUARY 2022; 1 YR 2 MOS

Involved in core processing and marketing tasks.

- Refactored legacy code that integrates CPA and payment processing, so integrating new ad network or payment system takes 3-5 days instead of month.
- Implemented custom per-block caching for dynamic landings for lowering load times and cpu cost.

MIDDLE PYTHON DEVELOPER AT DRIMTIM.IO, MOSCOW. MARCH 2018 – JANUARY 2021; 2 YRS 11 MOS

Implemented a lot of projects, from customising OpenStreetMap to writing high level drivers for storage systems and hypervisors orchestration system.

PYTHON ENGINEER; HONEYTEDDY. SEPTEMBER 2016 - MARCH 2018. 1 YR 7 MOS

Development of automation of internal business processes

Education

MComp, Computer Science and Informatics, Moscow Aviation Institute (National Research University), Moscow 2021.